CRISTIAN MARTIN ALARCON AGUIRRE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



I'm an Engineer with 4 years of experience in software development. My latest projects have allowed me to acquire skills as a full stack developer including frontend, backend, mobile app developing and databases handling, also as an electronic engineer I have experience with instrumentation, automation and renewable energy (Photovoltaic). I have effective organizational and communication Skills.

Work History

2021/07 – Current

Software Developer

SLONCORP CRIFA CIA. LTDA., Quito, Pichincha

- Developed software applications based on React JS, Loopback 4, SQL Server and Mongo DB.
- I'm familiarized with some AWS features like, Appflows, Lambda functions, RDS, ECS.
- Developed a full responsive web application for a US customer called BrightView.
- Developed a full responsive web application for client managing or Client Portal which is part of a bigger product called Fieldtech Connect.
- Tech leader in charge of "Brightview Enterprise Solutions Connect", "Fieldtech Connect Client Portal".
 Deployments and repository management using JIRA Bitbucket
- Worked along with US software developing company called Automated Decision
- Worked remotely with US Project Managers

2020/01 -2021/07

Software Developer

NIMBUSSOFT CIA. LTDA, Quito, Pichincha

- Front end (ReactJS, AngularJS, JQuery).
- Back end develop (Kotlin, NodeJS, .Net Core).
- Mobile developing (Flutter).

Contact

Address

Quito, Pichincha, 170522

Phone

(+593) 0969053256 /

E-mail

cristianma.2109@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/martin-fullstack

Skills

Software Development



Programming



Code versioning



Hardware and software installation



Technical design documentation



Data Bases SQL server, MongoDB

 Web Application based on React for the clients of Imperial (US Company dedicated to import and export products)

Web Application based on React and backend based on Kotlin for administrate the hole industrial and transportation process of Gadere (Ecuadorian Company dedicated to recollect and treat industrial and medical waste), also in this project I had to complete some correctional activities in the mobile platform (Java Android)

- Analysis and implementation of an administrative system for the EMELNORTE electric company, specifically in the acquisition, treatment and storage of measurements from the SMARTMATION luminaire integrated control platform.
- Worked along with RCB as the main developper of the mobile part of "Doctor Trace" (technological solution for any user who require access to a face-toface or virtual medical consultation with any registered medical specialist) I used Flutter along with agora.io, Firebase Cloud Messaging and others to develop two mobile apps one for patients and other for doctors

2018-09 - Meteorological Calibration Assistant

Escuela Politécnica Nacional, Quito

- Calibration of the meteorological station sensors of the University
- Main Responsibilities: Safe transportation of the complete weather station, to and from the Environment Secretary of Quito
- Care of the integrity of each part of the weather station during the calibration process
- Correct installation of the weather station
- Learning the operation of the entire station, in addition to the procedures for calibrating and maintaining weather sensors

2018-06 - Research Assistant

2018-12

2018-10

Escuela Politécnica Nacional, Quito

 Energy gain of a photovoltaic system due to solar tracking in one and two axes in equatorial regions with application to mobility systems: case of electric bicycles SQL integration

Excellent

Node.js



React



Flutter



Loopback



AWS



Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Advanced (Reading, writing, speaking).

Software

Really good at learn new abbilities in IT



- Main Responsibilities: Implementation of two independent photovoltaic systems, whose panels have solar tracking in one and two axes
- Implementation of a system for measuring and recording electrical variables for photovoltaic systems
- Optimization of the hardware and software of a station for recharging electric bicycles, powered by solar energy.

2018-03 - Laboratory Intern

2018-05

Escuela Politécnica Nacional, Quito

- Making printed circuits for semiconductors triggering
- Preventive and corrective maintenance of laboratory equipment
- Guide students for the use of the instruments.

2017-09 - Automation Intern

2017-10

UNACEM ECUADOR S.A, Otavalo

- Creation of a database with the most relevant information regarding the instruments found in the SCADA, implemented in SIMATIC PCS 7 process control system of SIEMENS
- Creation of a connection guide of instruments connected to each PLC 400 SIEMENS
- Analysis and sizing of a UPS system for the servers of the cement plant.

2017-02 - Engineering Intern

2017-03

Instituto Geográfico Militar, Quito

- Creation of a geo locator device with geocentric height reading in real time, as well as temperature, pressure and humidity
- Responsibilities: Acquisition and conditioning of signals from environmental conditions sensors.

2014-01 - Assistant Professor and Math & English 2014-10 Teacher

Curso de Nivelación "Stephen Hawking

 Teaching and application of differential and integral calculus (basic), English teacher at intermediate level

Education

2006-09 - High School Diploma

2012-09 Sánchez Y Cifuentes - Ibarra, Ecuador

2012-09 - Bachelor of Science: Electronics Engineering

2019-12 Technologies

Escuela Politécnica Nacional - Quito, Ecuador

Additional Courses

Python multipurpose

Udemy: ReactJS

Udemy: Flutter the complete guide

Udemy: Easy backend with Kotlin

Gnuplot 2D & 3D

Health and safety inside the industry

Electro-pneumatic controls

Participation "WORKSHOP FOR THE GENERATION OF RESEARCH NETWORKS IN PHYSICS AND TECHNOLOGY IN COLLABORATION WITH THE EUROPEAN

LABORATORY-CERN